Thank you for coming.
Let's start with the words
you love to hear:
"Welcome to Bible study!"
Today. my readin' ribbon's smack-dab
in the middle of Matthew 23.
Now let us download
the holy tweet of the Lord.
Stop making this relatable.
As a youth. if I don't hear
a computer word every sentence.
I am outta here.
Duly noted.
But we will make sure
not to dilute the sacred gospel.
Mousepad! Double click! Skype!
Skype!
Matthew 23:
"Then spake Jesus to the multitude.
and to his disciples. saying...."
My bathing suit came off!
It floats!
I'll handle this.
Schnell! Schnell!
You are the most infuriating.
Netflix DVD-burglaring.
barbecue-not-putting-out...
... man I ever met!
Hold that thought.
That man is beyond redemption.
That might seem to be true...
I sense a "but" coming.
Here comes the butt!
But I think you're up
to the challenge. Ned.
I've been working my Bible to the bone
trying to save that man.
Ned. God has never given up
on anyone.
What about Sodom and Gomorrah?
He lovingly destroyed them.
Instead of pushing Homer away.
can't you find a way
to reach out and bring him in?
Our Bible study group is going
to the Holy Land. next month.
I'd like you and your family
to come.
Let me think...
Take my family to a war zone.
on a bus
filled with religious lame-os.
in a country with no pork.
in a desert with no casinos...
Where do I sign up?
I can hear your sarcasm
from inside the house.
And the dishwasher's on!
What's going on here?
M. Flanders invited us to Israel.
He wants to get Dad into heaven.
Great. More hell for me.
Ned Flanders. you would take us
to the Holy Land
just to try to make my husband
a better man?
Yep. I also want to try something
called "pita bread."
Well. we will take you up
on your offer.
But we insist on paying our own way.
And Homer. put on some pants.
The man hates pants.
L'chaim!
Homie. tell them
what they want to hear.
I can't!
Latkes aren't as good
as American pancakes.
They're okay with apple sauce.
True enough.
A truckload of apple sauce!
Krusty. I've been meaning to ask.
What are you doing here?
I believe that every Jew
should make a pilgrimage to Israel
before he dies.
Yes. it is fitting.
Don't want to end up in hell.
- Jews don't believe in hell.
- No hell?
Thank you. kid. You made my day.
You're being paid
to clean the gutters!
This country's so historic.
For all we know.
Jesus could have given a talk
in conference room C.
Welcome!
My name is Jacob.
You may notice I speak the English
with a slight accent.
This is because.
as you've probably guessed.
I used to live in London.
and that is why I sound
like Hugh Grant.
Come on. Let's go.
We've got a lot of holy sites to see.
Yallah!
We finish early.
we go to jewelry store
owned by my cousins.
No joke. Is true. Great prices.
You got to haggle.
Otherwise they don't respect you!
Let's go!
Do you have any safety tips?
What are you talking about?
It's the safest country in the world.
The only danger here is dehydration.
Drink water. Don't die.
Looks bad on me.
Shut your face. Let's go.
But it says in the brochure...
Brochure?
Who wrote your brochure?
The same schmuck
who wrote the New Testament?
I can't talk to you.
You talk to my niece. Doreet.
Doreet. talk to the stupids.
Shalom. goyem!
Shalom to you!
Shalom is the aloha of this place.
Okay. lady.
You done talking now?
Who is licensed tour guide here.
you or me?
Now. everybody.
we have no time to see Masada.
Everybody died there for nothing.
Okay. first stop: Old City.
Let's go.
Shut your face!
The Old city.
Where BC turned into AD! Let's go!
Flanders. that stuff's been
here for thousands of years.
But the breakfast buffet
at the hotel.
which is included in our package.
closes in ten minutes!
Homer. that's not why we're here.
We can see the stations
of the cross.
After we see the stations
of the omelet bar.
Okay. let's just put it to a vote.
I can't believe we lost. reverend.
These blueberry muffins are bigger
than the ones we had at Pechanga.
Finally. something you like better
than Pechanga.
Okay. everybody.
Please shut your face. Here we go.
This sacred spot on Mount Zion
is King David's tomb.
Also. where your Jesus.
who was a native-born Israeli.
sandals. circumcised.
perfect English accent. the whole deal.
This is where
he had his last supper.
before they took him away
and hammered him up on that cross.
You're not part of the group.
No listening!
It's Israel. It's free country.
Okay. that's it.
Because of him. no Armenian quarter.
Forget it. It's gone.
All thanks to Mr. Listen-for-free.
Lord. please help Homer
experience the redemptive power
of this sacred land.
He's going for the record!
Flanders. you're not supposed
to help him.
Yeah. thanks a lot. Flanders.
Do you think you could show
the slightest bit of reverence?
Ned. I'm an American tourist.
I'm just here to see some sights.
try goofy new food
and spread some shekels
with my Carolina Panthers credit card.
Panthers!
Could you at least
turn the camera off?
If you say it like Dracula. I will.
Please...
That is going right
on stupidflanders.org.
You know. you might really benefit
from opening your heart
to the spirituality of this place.
Please. neighbor?
This really means a lot to you. huh?
Yes. but it means more to you.
Boy. are you lousy at reading minds.
For you. I'll try.
Lord. I think I may have
finally reached him...
Homer. quit playing that back.
I'm not. It's my ring tone.
Yello. This is he.
I wanted to know.
do you deliver falafels
to the top of Mount Zion?
Great. I'd like a large falafel
with pepperoni. sausage.
and extra cheese.
Yes. I know what a falafel is.
This...
Everybody. look at me.
This is the western.
or as you say. wailing wall.
It is believed that the Lord
will grant the prayers
that are stuck into the cracks.
Please. no graffiti.
no making the pishen. Yallah.
"Dear Lord: Please.
fix the following parking tickets:
"a647253.
"sp9.
"0325.
Shelbyville 932871..."
Sad.
Never gonna happen.
Maybe if you were Brad Pitt.
We're supposed to be acting religiousy.
What are you up to?
Reading prayers and ignoring them.
just like God.
This one's from you.
"Dear Lord. don't let Marge find out
the hotel leaves chocolates
on the pillows at night."
Why. you little...
"Give my dad another heart attack?"
Smite him
like the firstborn of Egypt.
Dead baby. dead baby. passover.
dead baby. dead baby...
Why am I running from a girl?
Call me when you're old enough
for your bat mitzvah.
I'll bring you an envelope
full of nothin'.
- Karate!
- Krav maga!
Krav ma-wha?
Israeli karate.
Less "hyah".
More "hyah"!
You don't fight like a girl.
Or even a Milhouse.
I don't know what is "Milhouse".
I work security for the tour.
Dealing with American punks like you
counts as my military service.
And we know all about you.
Ay. caramba.
Is that the ark of the covenant?
Karate!
Once again. krav maga!
Quit going for my groin!
No groin. no krav maga.
Hello. groin.
Come on. come on!
Everybody finish lemon ice.
not allowed inside.
Before us stands the church
of the Holy Sepulcher.
believed to be the home
of the tomb of your Lord.
Or as he's known here.
"the man in the underpants".
Beautiful tachtoonim.
What abs!
He was a real good-looking one.
Nice hair. Conditioner? I think so.
And. Lord. thank you for letting me
see this wonderful place
where the end of the world
will soon begin.
And thank you again for the challenge
of Homer Simpson.
We've all got our crosses to bear.
Me Homer. you...
the cross. And now.
let me gaze with reverence
upon the holy resting place that...
This is the most sacred spot
in Christendom.
not your backyard hammock!
I'm sorry.
It's just that these tours
are so exhausting.
You're jet-lagged.
You're walking around all day.
It's so hard to sleep
knowing Marge and the kids
are all stuck in one small room.
and...
It's so nice and cool
- in the tomb of the unknown savior.
- Unknown?!
This is the tomb of the most famous man
who ever lived!
- Porky pig?!
- Porky pig's not a man!
He's a pig.
and he's not even a real pig!
But he is buried here. right?
That's it! I'm losing it!
I'm losing it!
You come all the way to Jerusalem.
the happiest place on earth.
and all the photos in your camera
are of funny soda pops?!
Will you...
You are such a...
Chickpea fizz!
- Delete. Delete. Delete.
- Whatever. It's your camera.
Please.
you've got to let me back in.
I sold 6.000 rolls of wrapping paper
to get here.
That's your problem.
You. my friend.
are banned from ever entering
this church again.
B-banned for life?
Homer.
do you know why I'm a Christian?
- Your parents made you?
- It's because I believe every soul
has the possibility of salvation.
At least I thought so till now.
Homer Simpson.
you are not worth saving.
What? But I thought
we'd be neighbors in heaven.
- Goofing on all the new dead people.
- Not...
worth... saving!
Ned! Ned. wait up!
Ned's run off into the desert!
A sand horse... car of the desert!
Nothing like a tall glass of lukewarm
water to Jekyll down this Hyde.
Looks like a sandstorm's brewing.
I'll just wait it out at a movie.
Orthobot Prime.
the battle begins!
Not so fast...
We can't transform on the sabbath!
Let us power down
and contemplate the Torah.
Stupid Flanders!
There's sand in my shoe!
Good luck surviving without me!
Thirsty.
I am so thirsty
and hungry and horny
but mostly
just thirsty
I am so thirsty
Water!
So salty!
Maybe if I add a little salt.
You have been chosen. Homer.
Chosen for what. o mighty gherkin?
Rise and listen. my child.
Yours is a great destiny.
Carrot. tomato. pickle. carrot.
tomato. pickle. carrot. tomato...
Homie. you're alive!
I am more than alive. woman.
I am the chosen one
who shall unite all the faiths
of the Holy Land!
I am... the Messiah!
But you still have our passports.
right?
Oh. yeah.
Got to keep track of those.
The Messiah...
has the passports.
- Dad. are you okay?
- I am more than okay!
I am the Messiah.
come to save the world!
- Look upon me and shudder!
- I already do that.
Messiah?
- Can I have a word with your wife?
- As you wish.
But look not upon her with lust.
and do not send her friendly e-mails.
That's how it begins.
Homer is suffering from what's called
"Jerusalem syndrome."
Jerusalem syndrome:
the name given
to religious delusions or psychoses
that occur
when people visit Jerusalem.
Did you notice
Dad always gets the disease
they write about
in the in-flight magazine?
Homer's gone!
What's he gonna do now?
Dad said
he was going to unite all faiths.
Only one site is sacred
to Muslims. Christians and Jews.
- The Dome of the Rock!
- Dome of the Rock?
Messiah away!
{\$CERTIFIED PRE-OWNED
YARMULKES}
This one says "Carolina Panthers"!
Messiah says...
Okay. everybody. come on.
This shrine contains the rock
on which Abraham
was going to sacrifice his son.
And Muslims believe something too.
To find out.
hire a Muslim tour guide.
That's a barrel of laughs.
Anyway. shut your face.
Thanks.
You can stop giving the tour now.
You don't want a photo with me?
You can hold my gun.
I used it in Entebbe.
I killed three Ugandans.
Before you go in.
you fill out comment card.
- Don't forget the back.
- You people are so pushy.
What. Israeli people are pushy?
How about you experience genocides
and see how laid-back you are?
We were purged from Spain!
Throw out of there!
They allow everybody. there!
But for us. Jews.
no flamenco. get out!
I'm pushy?
Please.
You stay there.
surrounded
by your great enemy. Canada!
Try Syria for two months.
then we'll see who's pushy!
Attention.
Christians. Muslims and Jews:
I have come to gather you
into a new faith.
From now on. you shall be called...
Chrismujews.
I don't know.
Because when you get down to it.
aren't all religions the same?
They tell you what to eat.
when to pray.
how this imperfect clay
that we call man
can mold itself
to resemble the divine.
But we can never attain
that ultimate grace
while there is hatred in our hearts
for each other.
I did it.
I reached him.
Celebrate your commonality.
Some of us don't eat pork.
Some of us don't eat shellfish.
But all of us love chicken.
He's right!
- You can simmer it in a tagine.
- In a soup. you can boil it!
Spread the word!
Peace and chicken.
Peace and chicken!
Don't listen to this fat idiot!
I am your Messiah!
Avert your eyes
from my wrinkly arms!
Got another case
of Jerusalem syndrome.
This looks like a job for...
the Messiah!
I am the Messiah!
- I want the window seat!
- Krav maga!
You can't hurt what's already dead.
I guess you can.
Homer. my friend.
of all the false messiahs today.
I think you came
closest to the truth.
If I made any sense today.
it's because all the stuff
you've told me all these years
has finally seeped in.
Can I buy you a $12 turkey sandwich?
I'd like that.
How about a Greg Norman executive
putter from the Sky Mall?
You'd get a better deal
at a mall back home.
They have malls on land?
Why don't you try having your people
being thrown out of Spain?
Spain! No tapas!
I love eating tapas!
I love the tiny portions!
You don't get too full.
but you have a variety of flavors!
Not for me!
Every day hummus and pita!
Occasionally. once a week.
a little bit of falafel!